LE ANH NGOC

Ha Noi/Viet Nam • ngoc.leanh1999@gmail.com • 0975471213 • <u>linkedin.com/in/ngocla99</u>
github.com/ngocla99

Self-motivated, adaptable, and reliable with over 4+ years in Web Development, as well as strong ability to communicate and work in a team effectively, looking for an opportunity to leverage full stack coding proficiencies and grow as a professional programmer.

SKILLS

Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript.

Database Platform: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Firebase. Development Tools: VS Code, Figma, Postman, Xshell. Configuration Management Tools: Git, Github, Gitlab, SVN.

SDLC Methodologies: Agile, Scrum.

Testing & Others: Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, Sonarqube.

Soft Skills: Teamwork, adaptability, flexibility, problem solving, time management and prioritization.

Web Technologies, Framework & Library:

HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Material UI, Shadcn/ui, Ant Design, Styled-components.

ReactJS, Next.js, Angular.

Redux. Zustand.

Node.js, GrapQL, Express.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack developer Mar 2023 - Present
Ewoosoft VietNam Ha Noi

Description: Developed a dental clinic management website that tracked statistics related to partners, prosthesis, payments, and employees, while also supporting multiple languages.

Responsibilities:

- · Frontend:
 - Architected and developed scalable reusable UI components, forms, utility functions, router, and themes..., leading to a 20% reduction in feature development time and a 50% decrease in build time.
 - Optimized rendering in large list frontend, achieving a 80-95% reduction in load time.
 - Migrated project from Create React App (CRA) to Vite and upgraded Node.js from v16 to v20, cutting local development startup time from 1m30s to ~1.2s and production build time by 5x.
 - Removed over 1,000 unused files, 50 dependencies using Knip, significantly reducing code maintenance overhead.
 - Applied Apollo's **cache-and-network** policy, grouped GraphQL queries, and **optimistic updates** to improve data-fetching efficiency on the frontend.
 - Regularly reviewed code and **supported junior developers**, ensuring code quality, consistency, and best practices across the team.
 - Mentored and guided 2 team members in initiating a new mobile-first web project using modern technologies and best practices.
 - $\circ~$ Resolved complex UI challenges related to printing data.
- · Backend:
 - Refactored and optimized backend statistics APIs by replacing JavaScript-based processing with MongoDB aggregations, decreasing response time from **3–4 minutes to 2–3 seconds**.
 - Implemented targeted indexing strategies in the backend to optimize API performance, achieving a 40–50% reduction in response times.
 - Implemented feature flag system to selectively enable features for specific users, improving testing and rollout flexibility.
 - · Developed backend API functions and endpoints, migrated database, and resolved production issues.

Technologies: ReactJs, Tailwind, Shadon, Material UI, CKEditor, ApexCharts, use-Intl, Apollo, NodeJs, MongoDb, Docker, Kubernetes.

Front-end developer Aug 2022 - Mar 2023
FPT Software Ha Noi

Description: Developed a website that tracked statistics and issued warnings for user behaviors within the organization, company. Responsibilities:

- Developed & implemented all frontend features in collaboration with business analysts and designers.
- Created reusable components, hooks, and functions, ensuring modular and maintainable code.
- Ensured code quality by scanning libraries with SonarQube.
- Automated CI/CD pipeline using GitLab CI/CD and deployed with Docker.

Technologies: ReactJs, Redux-Saga, Ant Design, Styled Components, ChartJs, NodeJs, MongoDb, Elastichsearch, Docker.

Front-end developer Jan 2022 - Jul 2022
FPT Software Ha Noi

Description: Migrated DEN system from Flex to HTML/Angular.

Responsibilities:

- Developed UI common components.
- Contributed to building the project base.
- Assisted team members in resolving hard issues and tasks.

Technologies: Angular, SQL, Boostrap5, HTML, CSS3.

PROJECTS

Shopping Cart

Description: Create an e-commerce platform with login and logout capabilities. Users are able to add items to their cart, make payments, and leave reviews for products. Admins have the ability to manage and update products, orders, and user accounts.

Responsibilities:

- Developed the base project, delegate tasks, and provide support to team members (leader).
- Developed Home screen and Profile screen.
- Authentication and Authorization using JWT and Refresh Token.
- · Import and export Excel files.

Technologies: ReactJs, Bootstrap 5, TypeScript, HTML, CSS3, Firebase, Figma, Postman.

Blog App

Description: Create a blog website with basic social media features, including posting, deleting, and editing articles. Users can also favorite or unfavorite posts, and edit their profiles.

Responsibilities:

- Developed the base project, delegate tasks, and provide support to team members (leader).
- Developed profile screen, create new post, update information.
- Developed Share module (reuse directive, pipe, component).

Technologies: Angular, Bootstrap 5, TypeScript, HTML, CSS3, Firebase, NgRx.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Automation Control

Sep 2017 - Jul 2021

Hanoi University of Science and Technology

GPA: 3.21